Finding Aid for Drama Season (University of Michigan) records, 1929-1966
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Drama Season (University of Michigan) records 1929-1966
University of Michigan. Drama Season.
3 linear feet.
85643 Bimu N5 2
ABSTRACT
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The records have come to the library in periodic accessions (Donors 3190, 3799, and 8330 ).
Periodic additions to the records expected.
The records are open to research.
Drama Season was founded by Robert Henderson in 1929. The organization was originally known as the Ann Arbor Dramatic Season Committee. It's mission was to bring professional level theater to Ann Arbor, and until 1942 a festival was held each spring at the Lydia Mendelssohn Theater in the Michigan League. The season featured distinguished artists performing in a wide range of classic, experimental and popular productions.
Performances were cancelled in 1943 due to wartime demands and did not resume until 1949. The 1949 season was launched within the traditional framework of a five-week festival, drawing performers from both Broadway and Hollywood. Drama Season, as it came to be known, was sponsored by an area civic committee, including representatives from the university and local citizens.
The organization maintained an office in the Lydia Mendelssohn Theatre. Student participation was encouraged on stage in bit parts and off stage with the stage crew and in costuming and ushering.
Serving as resident directors, in addition to founder Robert Henderson, were Charles Hohman, John O'Shaughnessy, Helen Arthur, Agnes Morgan, and Valentine Windt.
The Drama Season records span the years 1929-1966. The material consists of scrapbooks from 1938 to 1942 and 1949 to 1961 (2 linear ft.) which contain mainly clippings from local and national newspapers, along with some programs and photographs.
Also included are alphabetically arranged administrative files relating to the operation of the theater and the performances. Materials include correspondence, legal and financial files and press releases. The bulk of this material is from the 1950s and 1960s.
The photographs series inclusdes a photo album and production photographs, mostly from the 1950s and autographed photos of Lillian Gish and Billie Burke.
Subjects:
Actors.; Ann Arbor (Mich.); Ann Arbor Drama Season.; Theater --Michigan--Ann Arbor.; University of Michigan--Dramatics.; University of Michigan. Drama Season.
Subjects - Visual Materials:
Theatrical productions.
Contributors:
Henderson, Robert.; O'Shaughnessy, John.; Windt, Valentine, 1901-1955.
Genre Terms:
Photographs.; Scrapbooks.
- Scrapbooks
  - 1938-1942, 1949-1952 (10 vol.) (Box 1)
  - 1953-1961, 9 vol. (Box 2)
- Records
  - Board Meetings, 1961-1964 (Box 3)
  - Bylaws and Incorporation, 1960 (Box 3)
  - Clippings, 1957-1964 (Box 3)
  - Correspondence, 1931-1935, 1946-1951, 3 folders (Box 3)
  - Financial Records, 1935-1964, 8 folders (Box 3)
  - Legal Papers, 1949-1960, 1962, 3 folders (Box 3)
  - Miscellaneous, 1934-1957 (Box 3)
  - Press Releases, ca. 1960-1966, 4 folders (Box 3)
  - Stage Drawing, Lydia Mendelssohn Theatre, Women's League Building, Ann Arbor, Michigan, undated (Box 3)
- Photographs
  - Album, Drama Season of 1955 (production photographs) (Box 3)
  - Autographed: Lillian Gish and Billie Burke, circa. 1950s (Box 3)
  - Miscellaneous production photographs, ca. 1950s, 3 folders (Box 3)
  - "The Reluctant Debutante," 1957 "The Sleeping Prince," 1957 "Witness for the Prosecution," 1957. (Box 3)